Huh? My mum?
Yeah. Your dad always comes to pick you up, right?
Daikichi's not my dad.
My dad is Granddad.
That's weird!
Everyone has a mum and a dad!
So who's Daikichi, then?
I don't know...
What?
Rin-chan says really weird stuff.
Men can't have babies.
Shut up!
You don't need a dad!
Morons!
Takes one to know one...
Morons! Morons! Morons!
Hiro-sensei!
Come on!
Kouki-kun called me a moron!
Kouki-kun was calling us morons!
Hiro-sensei!
Is your family just you and your mum?
My dad ran off, so she divorced him.
What does "divorce" mean?
It's when two grown-ups stop being married.
I wonder if that's why my mum's gone, too.
I don't know.
You'll get scolded if you don't wear your hat.
What is it?
You've stretched the cord...
Rin-chan! Someone's here for you!
Rin-chan!
It's Daikichi!
Someone's here to pick you up!
Rin-chan... Someone's...
It's okay, Maa-kun!
Thank you!
See you later, Rin-chan!
Bye!
What should we have for dinner?
Kouki-kun!
Your mother's here to pick you up!
Usagi
Drop
I can't tell what'll come tomorrow.
ashita no koto wa wakaranai
明日のことはわからない
This is different than making a sacrifice.
kore tte gisei to wa chigau
これって犠牲とは違う
Something about it is different.
nanika ga chigau
何かが違う
And I don't think of it as some sort of forfeit.
batsu geemu ja nante omowanai
罰ゲームじゃなんて思わない
So I just don't get why.
...tte nande na no ka wakaranai
...ってなんでなのか分からない
I can't quite wrap my head around it,
chotto shakuzen to shinai kedo
ちょっと釈然としないけど
but your existence is now much more than just important to me.
kimi no sonzai ima daiji da nante mon ja nai
君の存在今大事だなんてもんじゃない
There's nothing in this world that doesn't come to an end.
owaranai koto nante kono yo no doko ni mo nai
終わらないことなんてこの世のどこにもない
I don't cry because I'm hurting.
naku no wa tsurain ja nai no
泣くのは辛いんじゃないの
They're the sweet, sweet drops of love!
ai no sweet drops sweet drops
愛の sweet drops sweet drops
I want to go on dreaming forever, you know?
zutto yume mite mitai ne
ずっと夢見てみたいね
I want to try and be more gentle, you know?
motto yasashiku shitai ne
もっと優しくしたいね
If I can be with you, I'm happy.
kimi to iraretara happy
君といられたらhappy
Girls are really strong, aren't they?
onna no ko tte tsuyoi ne
女の子って強いね
But sometimes, they can be really weak, you know?
dakedo tokidoki yowai ne
だけど時々弱いね
Our wishes are happy, happy, happy.
bokura no negai wa happy happy happy
僕らの願いは happy happy happy
And our days will be just as happy!
sonna hibi mo happy
そんな日々も happy
Just wanna make you happy!
Your mum's so pretty!
She's a grumpy old lady at home, though!
U-Um...
She's always such a big help to Kouki.
R-Really?
My son's kind of blunt, so he doesn't make friends very easily...
Thank you very much.
N-No, not at all!
Rin's pretty quiet, too, so...
Guess it's a case of birds of a feather?
Daikichi, you were talking about me, weren't you?
It wasn't anything bad.
Go on ahead.
I don't want you telling me to carry you halfway again.
I'm not going to!
Let's go!
Is she a bit of a Daddy's girl?
N-No, I'm not her father.
I'm sort of a relative, or... Well...
I-I'm sorry, what am I saying?!
N-Not at all...
Mum, hurry up!
It's nice that you made a friend.
Yeah!
Kouki-kun said he doesn't have a dad.
He said his dad got divorced and went off somewhere.
You know what a divorce is, Rin?
Yeah. When a marriage ends, right?
W-Well, pretty much...
If God knew about that, he'd probably punish those people, right...?
W-Well...
I wonder if my mum isn't here because of a divorce, too...
Do you want to meet her?
I don't know...
I see.
But you know,
if she's like Kouki-kun's mum, I definitely do!
Me, too! Me, too!
What?!
Rin-chan's mother is...?!
Yeah. I think her mother is probably the maid who worked at Granddad's.
I don't believe it...
Did you hear anything about the maid?
This was pretty good!
A farewell party? For me?
Sorry we're having it so late.
Orders for winter clothing have finally died down a little.
Thanks.
But I can't really go out at night.
My kid's only six.
You mean that you haven't been out drinking since...
Yeah. It can't really be helped.
And I've sort of stopped caring about drinking and stuff.
Maybe I'm just too old for it.
You're only thirty...
Plus, even though the guys in my department are young,
a lot of them have kids,
so it's not really customary for them to go out drinking.
Right?
You've got that right.
I have to go pick up my kid from nursery.
My wife gave birth to two kids last year, and the younger one's only three months old.
So if I don't go straight home...
She gives you hell, right?
You really don't want to make her mad.
Kawachi-kun!
Gotou-san.
I heard about the farewell party!
But night's not a good time for me.
It'd be a shame to let it go to waste, though.
How about you bring her with you?
I'll bring mine, too!
Are you just looking for an excuse to go dr-
Hey, don't worry! It'll be fine, right?
I'm looking forward to it!
Coming, coming...
Daikichi. Phone.
Thanks.
Hello?
Ah, Daikichi?
It seems that your grandfather had a
regular maid dispatched by an agency.
Hey, hey. Wait a second...
Did you find out her name?
Yoshii Masako-san. The "masa" is the kanji for "correct", and the "ko" is the one for "child".
That's the name on the mother and child health record, isn't it?
Looks like it.
Are you going to get in touch with her?!
With the sort of person who left behind such a lovely-
Calm down a bit!
You saw the health record, right?
There's a whole bunch of stuff written in there.
And there's still so much we don't know.
Excuse me!
What I'm saying is...
...that I can't tell the difference between work and home anymore.
Sorry I'm late.
Hey, you're late!
Stay away! Damn drunk!
Rin-chan?
You came!
Thank you!
You're so cute!
Eat up!
Here you go.
Thanks for coming, Rin-chan.
Thank you!
Here you go, Rin-chan.
Is orange juice okay?
Yeah.
Rin-chan's a beauty, huh?
Sure is!
She's blushing!
I'll gather it up for you, Yuu-kun.
Thanks, Rin-chan.
Kawachi-san, you need to have a few more drinks.
Rin might get sleepy on the way home, so...
Rin, I'm going to the bathroom.
Call it the toilet!
Right, right... I'm going to the toilet.
He bailed on our department, you know.
Don't produce results if you're only going to stop halfway, right?
Pretty ugly to just quit while you're ahead.
Sales have taken a pretty bad turn this month, too.
And even if we do a decent job, the big shots are just going to compare it to last year.
What should we do?
GENTLEMEN
Can't believe it.
The old me would've stormed in there with guns blazing, but...
Geez. I feel like I'm going to pee myself...
Little girls are really soft!
I wish you were my kid!
Some really important part of me has changed, hasn't it?
Kawachi-san...
About your transfer...
I kind of understand after meeting Rin-chan.
I know, right?
Mama, mama...
I just want to squish you forever!
Hold me, too!
Gotou-san, Rin-chan doesn't like that...
Masako-san...
How did you feel about your kid? About Rin?
Yuu-kun was really cute, wasn't he?
You sure love little kids, huh?
Yep! The mail's here.
Thanks.
Oh! It says here that they're having an informational meeting about junior school admittance.
Can't believe this turned up without me doing anything.
What's wrong?
There's an entrance test, right?
No! No!
You can get in without taking any test.
Really?
Of course!
Compulsory education is great, right?
Drunk...
Damn! How about this?
Rin-chan, he's here!
I-I'm sorry...
Hey! Everyone else has left already.
S-Sorry...
Kouki-kun! Your mother's here!
I'm sorry, Kouki...
H-Hello.
It's been... a while...
Daikichi, are we going to make it?
I'll grab a taxi!
Thank you!
The children's name tags are reversible...
...so that they can be hidden on the way home from school.
We also ask that you do not leave them alone, even at parks and places like that,
and that you make sure they don't go off with someone, even if it's someone familiar.
It's tough, isn't it?
Having to teach them to be suspicious of people...
...instead of trusting them.
Yeah...
Ah, that sheet we were given...
Oops!
I've got them. I've got them!
How am I supposed to know what vaccinations she's already had?
Huh?
S-Sorry...
Apparently that was a weird question to ask...
Not at all. Do you have Rin-chan's health record?
Yeah, at home.
There's a page for recording it in there.
So don't worry.
I see...
I really don't know anything.
I only met Rin about three months ago.
Three months?
Yeah...
I'm surprised.
It feels like she really trusts you.
I wonder...
She talks back a lot at home, and she nags me a bunch...
That's just proof of her trust.
Anyone could see that the two of you are a family.
A family...
R-Really?
Of course!
I wonder...
What?
Just jumping over your shadow.
I'm not tired!
It's fine.
Let me down!
I said let me down!
Thanks.
We've got most of it.
Huh?
A school bag?
We don't have one yet.
That's no good!
All of the fancy and designer ones'll be sold out already!
A normal one's fine.
It is not. She's a girl, after all.
Fine, I'll have a look this weekend.
Dai-chan... Are you just going to keep raising Rin-chan?
You moved to another division, right?
I haven't really thought that far ahead yet, but...
Mama!
I'll do yours this time!
Okay.
You two are really close, huh?
Yeah. Mothers and daughters are like friends.
Now that I think about it, Mum and Kazumi get along pretty well, too...
And it's not impossible that Masako-san's situation could've changed...
...so that she'd want to live with her daughter...
She's had so many shots.
I guess her mum really must have...
Huh?
Souichi's Will
Boing!
A will!
"Boing"?
TL Note: Daikichi is struggling to read because they've been written by someone who is computer illiterate, and half of the kanji have been entered incorrectly.
"If Masako found my will, she'd probably just destroy it,"
"so I decided to go about things in a slightly more... bothersome way."
"But I can't work out how to properly hide this... or post this or anything like that."
"And this... keyboard thing is making fun of me,"
"so it's taking me forever to enter anything."
Those are some major kanji mistakes.
"My old body has grown terribly weary..."
"...so I've decided to abandon this blog."
Giving up already?
You ought to have a little persistence when you're that old.
"I'll continue the rest in Rin's health record."
Sorry, Rin. I'll just take a little look.
"I trust that the person who finds this sheet..."
"...will be one who holds Rin close to his or her heart."
"I intend to record in here details pertaining to Rin and her mother, Masako."
"Masako is the kind of person who is often misunderstood,"
"so I wish to preface this by saying that she is by no accounts a terrible young lady."
"She feels that she isn't fit to be a mother,"
"that it wouldn't be fair to Rin."
"She also insists on serving as my maid, even now,"
"and I'm sure she will continue to do so."
"I believe she feels as if that is the most she can do to make Rin happy."
To make Rin happy...?
What's that supposed to mean?
"She lives every moment of her life while making sure that if anything were to happen to me,"
"there would be no trace of her existence that any of my relatives would find."
"There is no doubt that Masako loves Rin as only a mother could."
"Yet she is still so young, and perhaps lacks the maturity to be a parent."
I don't really get it.
Though it's clear that he really cared about Rin and her mother, at least.
Yoshii Masako
Daikichi.
What is it?
Listen...
I want you to make my hair look like bunny ears!
Huh?
Like Reina-chan's mum did before.
I can't!
Do it!
I can't! There's no way I can do that!
I said do it!
Because...
Someone said I wasn't cute.
Huh?
Someone told you that?
Mii-chan said I wasn't cute at all...
Huh?
I think Rin pretty much wins by default...
I want to be cute, too.
Fine, fine...
She's already grown up enough that comments like that really hurt.
Do you realise, Masako-san,
that Rin's already so mentally mature?
Actually, no... There are parts of her that are, and parts that still aren't.
That's exactly why she needs an adult to look out for her.
Fin... ished...
T-This is...
Oh, star up in the sky...
Hey, Rin...
Glittering aw-
What are you doing?
We're supposed to keep the talent show a secret from our parents.
Huh? Talent show?
So you can't watch!
S-She's going to do it while wearing that hairstyle?
Oh, star up in the sky...
Yoshii Masako
Glittering away...
If you left Rin alone,
telling yourself that it didn't matter if it was painful, because she'd forget in time...
Your twinkling eyes blink...
...as you watch over everyone...
I'll hate you without so much as a second thought.
Oh, star up in the sky...
I'm praying that you at least had a good reason.
But...
Glittering away...
What sort of reason could actually make you leave your own child?
Study desk
Study chair
This is cute!
It's cute,
but if you're going to be using it for a long time,
it'd be better to go with something a bit more...
Oh, I know!
Wouldn't a desk for a big girl be better?
A big girl?
Yeah! One for a big girl!
Yes!
You're sitting there again?
Do I look like a big girl?
Yeah.
I think you could probably use that desk even once you're a high school student.
A high school student... Will I be a grown-up then?
Hm... Maybe a half-grown-up.
Book: Goldilocks and the Three Bears
Listen to me read!
"A girl went to play on her own in the forest."
"The girl got lost and looked for the path going back home."
"But she just couldn't find it."
"Before she knew it, she came across a little house in the forest."
Is this Yoshii-san?
Huh? Y-Yes...
A sunny Sunday's early afternoon;
nichiyou no hareta hirusagari
日曜の晴れた昼下がり
where should we go today?
kyou wa doko e yukou?
今日はどこへ行こう？
The same old road that I'm so used to walking on...
kayoinareta itsumo no michi ga
通い慣れたいつもの道が
...shines with a dazzling light.
mabushiku kagayaite mieru
眩しく 輝いて見える
If I have the warm sunlight shining down on me...
terasu atatakai taiyou to
照らす暖かい太陽と
...and you by my side...
tonari ni kimi ga ireba...
隣に君がいれば
Whoa! High, high, high!
My feelings are ready to burst forth.
hashagidasu kimochi ni
はしゃぎだす気持ちに
Sing out, lai lai lai!
utae lai lai lai!
歌え lai lai lai!
My voice reaches every corner of the earth.
koe wa doko made mo
声はどこまでも
I'm already high, high, high!
mou high high high!
もう high high high!
Riding the whirling winds...
maiagaru kaze ni nori
舞い上がる風に乗り
Sing out, lai lai lai!
utae lai lai lai!
歌え lai lai lai!
My voice swoops up and down with me.
koe mo tobihaneru
声も飛び跳ねる
This is cute, huh?
N-Not again! Rin?!
Rin?!
Hey!
Daikichi...
I told you not to disappear on me like that!
Okay...
What's that?
Something that'll make me into a big girl!
No way!
This is for much later on!
Why?